Guide to the Rick Lang Photographs of Florida and Other Southern States, 1985-2013 RL.11372
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Photographs, 1990-2013; 1; 10.5 Linear Feet 8 boxes 229 prints
  - Happy Days Diner, Pikeville, Kentucky, 1997 (Box 6, Image RL-11372-P-0206)
  - We're Open, Virginia, 2006 (Box 6, Image RL-11372-P-0207)
    Original contact sheet number: 181
  - Bethlehem No. 1, Mississippi, 2006 (Box 8, Image RL-11372-P-0208)
    Original contact sheet number: 229
  - Back of bar, Clarksdale, Mississippi, 2006 (Box 8, Image RL-11372-P-0209)
  - Not Amtrak Office, Okeechobee, Florida, 2005 (Box 8, Image RL-11372-P-0210)
  - Restroom, Osteen Bridge, Florida, 2003 (Box 8, Image RL-11372-P-0211)
    Original contact sheet number: 166
  - Cantina, near Ft. Mead, Florida, 2000 (Box 8, Image RL-11372-P-0212)
    Original contact sheet number: 118
  - Cotton Gin, Cottondale, Florida, 2003 (Box 8, Image RL-11372-P-0213)
    Original contact sheet number: 223
  - Native art, Helena, Arkansas, 2006 (Box 8, Image RL-11372-P-0214)
    Original contact sheet number: 232
  - Uncle Joe's, U.S. 27, Florida, 2003 (Box 8, Image RL-11372-P-0216)
    Original contact sheet number: 168
  - J.A. Barthel Store, east side of the River Road, Louisiana, 2009 (Box 8, Image RL-11372-P-0217)
  - Shed, Highway 8, Louisiana, 2009 (Box 8, Image RL-11372-P-0218)
  - Auto Salvage, Slidell, Louisiana, 2009 (Box 8, Image RL-11372-P-0219)
  - Cemetery, west side of the River Road, Louisiana, 2009 (Box 8, Image RL-11372-P-0220)
  - Highway 61 & 49, near Clarksdale, Mississippi, 2009 (Box 8, Image RL-11372-P-0221)
  - Flynn MFG Co., Alexandria, Louisiana, 2009 (Box 8, Image RL-11372-P-0222)
  - Bobby's T.V. Service, Alexandria, Louisiana, 2009 (Box 8, Image RL-11372-P-0223)
  - Bar, Mamou, Louisiana, 2009 (Box 8, Image RL-11372-P-0224)
  - St. Gabriel Grocery, east side of the River Road, Louisiana, 2009 (Box 8, Image RL-11372-P-0225)
  - Woods Westside Fish Market, Minden, Louisiana, 2009 (Box 8, Image RL-11372-P-0226)
  - Amanda's Haircut Shop, Belleview, Florida, 1998 (Box 8, Image RL-11372-P-0227)
    Original contact sheet number: 177
  - Hollandale Seed & Delinting, Rosedale, Mississippi, 2006 (Box 8, Image RL-11372-P-0228)
    Original contact sheet number: 247
  - Jazz Feed, Baker, Florida, 2003 (Box 8, Image RL-11372-P-0229)
  - Gatorland sign, Florida, 1998 (Box 8, Image RL-11372-P-0230)
    Original contact sheet number: 134
- Contact Sheets, 1990-2013
  Series contains contact sheets created from original negatives, typically bearing 14-15 black-and-white images. Contact sheet 258 is not present in the collection; however, the corresponding images are available in the negatives series. The total number of images available from the contact sheets is roughly 3500.
  - Contact sheet numbers: 1-160 (Box 9)
  - Contact sheet numbers: 161-259 (Box 10)
    Contact sheet 258 is not present.
- Negatives, 1990-2013
  Conditions Governing Access
  Original negatives are closed to general use; access available only by permission of the curator for the Archive of Documentary Arts.
  The negatives are arranged in groups corresponding to the contact sheet content and numbering. The majority are 35mm, but there are also a few 128mm and a few 4x5 inch sizes. Negatives from contact sheet 258, which is not present in collection, are available in this series.
  - Negative groups: contact sheet numbers 1-160 (Box 11)
  - Negative groups: contact sheet numbers 161-259 (Box 12)
- Printed Materials, 1985-2013; 1 box, 1 oversize folder; approximately 40 pieces
  Series includes photography publications, articles, publicity, and obituaries, assembled by Rick Lang's colleague and Executive Director of the Creadlé School of Art in Winter Park, Florida, Peter Schreyer. Three photo books and exhibit catalogues offer many images by Lang not found in this collection's prints, particularly portraits of central Florida people by Lang and other photographers. One exhibition poster is filed in box 5.
  - Oversize publication, 2008 June (Box 5)
  - Exhibition poster, undated (Box 5)
  - Publications, 1985-2012, 1 folder; 3 bound items (Box 13)
    Publications with work by Rick Lang. in addition to two magazine articles, includes a set of three soft-cover photography books and exhibit catalogues documenting central Florida communities, featuring work by Rick Lang and others; here one can find Lang's many portraits of Floridians, most of which are not present in the collection as finished prints.
  - Publicity, 1991-2008 (Box 13)
    Folder houses exhibit flyers, brochures, and articles about Rick Lang and his photographic work.
  - Obituaries, condolences, and tributes, 2013 (Box 13)
    Folder of materials includes a message from Excecutive Director Peter Schreyer to the faculty and artists of Creadlé School of Art, where Rick Lang taught, on Lang's death, July 9, 2013. Accompanied by a photocopy of the obituary from the Orlando Sentinel, and condolence and tribute emails from colleagues and friends.
- Digital Files, 1993-2013; bulk 2008-2011; 6.50 gigabytes; 130 digital files.
  Digital files are open to research, but access may require advance preparation. Please contact the Rubenstein Library before coming to use these materials.
  Selected images from 1993 to 2013 are available in .psd (Adobe Photoshop) digital file format created by Lang. Also includes original photographer's inventory of prints in collection.